[Music]
the pre-hospital
emergency care council commonly known as
feck
is an independent statutory health care
regulator
with responsibility for standards
education and
training in the field of pre-hospital
emergency care its core mission is to
protect the public through the promotion
of excellence in pre-hospital emergency
care
cova 19 is a highly infectious disease
which can cause
serious illness hospitalization and even
death
thankfully due to the excellent and
timely work of scientists all over the
world
we have reached the stage where a number
of vaccines have been developed
ireland will now see a national rollout
of the vaccine as the various
medications are approved for use
the authority to allow registered
pre-hospital practitioners to administer
the vaccine
has just been signed into law by the
government of ireland
in response feck have acted quickly to
develop clinical practice guidelines to
support administration of the first
two approved vaccines by fec registrants
and it's likely that other vaccines will
follow as they become approved
there are currently over 5 300 fec
registrants registered emts paramedics
and
advanced paramedics who are now
authorized and available to the system
and can be called upon to participate in
the national vaccination program
as vaccinators approximately two and a
half thousand of these
work for the two statutory providers
which leaves upwards of two and a half
thousand
additional trained and registered vet
practitioners who could be available to
assist with the administration of covet
19 vaccines
every pre-hospital registered
practitioner has been previously trained
in the administration of intramuscular
injections
and is trained to recognize and manage
allergic reactions
and anaphylaxis they are also trained to
perform basic life support
the pre-hospital emergency care council
and its registered healthcare
practitioners are playing their part in
this important initiative
feck have moved very rapidly to create
clinical practice guidelines
and medication formularies to
effectively support
fec registered practitioners perform
vaccine administration
it is strongly recommended that everyone
get the vaccine as soon as it is
available to them
you should be aware that people who are
most at risk from covet 19
will get the vaccine first and that the
vaccine is free
information on the vaccine is available
at hse.ie
look for covid19 vaccine
[Music]
you